L’Aerophile Collection
Science, Technology, & Business Division, Library of Congress
- Photographs (Box 45-74)
  - Misc. Photos by country. (Box 62)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: Franco-American. (Envelope 4)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: Germany. (Envelope 5)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: Italy. (Envelope 6)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: Spain. (Envelope 7)
    - Miscellaneous Photos: USA. (Envelope 8)
  - Parachutes. (Box 63)
    - Parachutes (England). (Envelope 1)
      - Blueprint describing how to deploy a parachute. (Item 1)
      - Series of three photographs showing a young woman and the series of steps taken to fly with a parachute attached to one’s body. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of Eddy Swan wearing his parachute - London, 1934. (Item 3)
      - Reenactment of Hendon air show. (Item 4)
      - Respected landing parachutist, John Tranum, lands in Salisbury, England. (Item 5)
      - Photograph of Ivor Price descending immediately after leaving the plane. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of parachutist dropped from a plane and maneuvering to resume equilibrium. (Item 7)
      - Photogrpah of an unidentified parachutist. (Item 8)
    - Parachutes (France). (Envelope 2)
      - Series of six photographs (in waxy envelope) detailing proper parachute attachment. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of parachutist in field holding his Aviorex parachute. (Item 2)
      - Creative photograph of three separated belts used to secure parachute. (Item 3)
      - Series of two photographs highlighting the seatbelts of an airplane. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of man in suit demonstrating a parachute’s belt features. (Item 5)
      - Photograph showcasing a parachutist’s helmet, belt and straps. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of 26 parachutists in line next to plane while holding equipment. (Item 7)
      - Three photographs of parachutist in initial descent prior to pulling parachute. (Item 8)
      - Three photographs of parachutists in flight. (Item 9)
      - Air Military festival in French town of Le Bourget. Photograph shows parachute landing. (Item 10)
      - Photograph of parachutes in flight. (Item 11)
      - Photograph of young French parachute champion, James Williams. Williams was to attempt an 800-meter descent. Other photograph shows Williams after the successful landing. (Item 12)
      - Photograph of aerial maneuvers near French town of Montdidier. During the course of a balloon observatory attack by aircraft, the observer parachuted out of the plane. (Item 13)
      - Photograph of time before parachute descent near Le Bourget. (Item 14)
      - Photograph of parachutist sporting Aviorex parachute which is worn on the back. (Item 15)
      - Three photographs of landed parachute. (Item 16)
      - Two photographs of parachutist attempting to beat the record for parachute descent in 1937 of 12,000 meters. (Item 17)
      - Four photographs of parachutist in flight from the School of Parachutists at Tousses. (Item 18)
      - Monsieur Denois, surrounded by his students, shows the parachute cable fixed by one end to the aircraft allowing some development of the aircraft. (Item 19)
      - Photograph of time before the flight, students practicing exiting the aircraft. (Item 20)
      - Photograph of man securing his parachute straps. (Item 21)
      - Photograph of Mademoiselle Bonte during her descent. (Item 22)
      - Photograph of two men in grounded balloon trying out a new piece of rescue equipment. (Item 23)
      - Two men experimenting with model-size rescue equipment. (Item 24)
      - Photograph of parachute landing in water. (Item 25)
      - Aerial photograph of nearly two dozen parachutists in flight. (Item 26)
      - Photograph of airborne man before parachute deployment. (Item 27)
      - Photograph of 180-meter jump into a ravine. (Item 28)
      - Two photographs of doctor attending to Rene Machenau after a parachuting accident. (Item 29)
      - Photograph of miniature parachute. (Item 30)
      - Two photographs of parachutist landing. (Item 31)
      - Photograph men securing parachutist’s equipment prior to plane’s takeoff. (Item 32)
      - Monsieur Rene Courtin attempts to parachute from a balloon from a height of 50 meters, setting a new world record. In photograph, Courtin is shown dangling from the bottom of the balloon near the ground. (Item 33)
      - Men examine M. Courtin’s parachute after his flight. The openings in the parachute’s wings are quite visible. (Item 34)
      - Photograph of M. Dupuis and his folded parachute ready to go up in the plane. (Item 35)
      - Photograph of female parachutist with man. (Item 36)
      - Aerial photograph of parachutist prior to parachute deployment. (Item 37)
      - Nine unidentified photographs. (Item 38)
    - Parachutes (USA). (Envelope 3)
      - Series of four photographs. First three show a parachutist descending in San Diego. The last photograph shows the parachutist smiling after a successful landing. (Item 1)
      - Mr. Harvey K. Lafayette with is new parachute. (Item 2)
      - Set of two photographs. First of a man with a Russell parachute and the second showing a closer view of the Russell parachute. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of landed parachute. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of several airborne parachutists. (Item 5)
      - Amelia Earhart tries a new parachute. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of nine grounded parachutists after their descent. (Item 7)
      - Mr. Oswell A. Baker came to California to experiment with a new parachute which he invented. After 300 experiments, the parachute was still functioning successfully. Mr. Baker is shown on the right with P.C. Davis and the parachutist Wm Frauenberger. (Item 8)
      - Series of two photographs showing an American parachutist as he exits the plane amid his descent into Barksdale Field in Louisiana. (Item 9)
      - Photograph of cabinet of parachutes at camp. (Item 10)
      - Photograph of airplane with parachute above displaying: “WINGS.” (Item 11)
      - Photograph of Herbert Shorty Stark as he attempts to break a parachute record in Los Angeles. (Item 12)
      - Set of two photographs showing the American air ambulance equipped with a parachute. (Item 13)
      - Set of two photographs showing Jerry Wessling, winner of the spot parachute jumping contests during his winning leap. He landed in the middle of a white circle of 50 feet in circumference in the center of the field, showing perfect control of his chute. (Item 14)
      - Photograph of Clem Sohn of Lansing, Michigan after his descent to the terrain of Hanworth, Middlesex along with 50,000 spectators. (Item 15)
      - Photograph of the first “live rider” of the universal high compression parachute, then a new aerial safety device of remarkable small size and efficiency, designed by Oswell A. Baker. (Item 16)
      - Photograph of man holding unreleased parachute. (Item 17)
      - Photograph of parachutists during his initial descent before parachute deployment; plane is shown in photograph. (Item 18)
      - One unidentified photograph. (Item 19)
    - Parachutes (Germany). (Envelope 4)
      - Photograph from the film, “Flieger,” showing a man landing his parachute near a shore. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of a parachute jump from a Montgolfière (balloon inflated with heated air) next to the Berlin radio tower. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of man jumping from a Montgolfière with a parachute. (Item 3)
    - Parachutes (Italy). (Envelope 5)
      - Italian parachutist posing on ground with parachute prior to deployment. (Item 1)
      - Two photographs of man donning parachute belt equipment. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of parachute belt apparatus. (Item 3)
      - Photograph taken from the ground of 20 airmen bearing parachutes along with several airplanes. (Item 4)
      - Large photograph of eight airmen with parachutes as the parachutes begin to deploy. (Item 5)
    - Parachutes (Poland). (Envelope 6)
      - Photograph of Polish parachutist. Like the USSR, Poland wanted to acquaint itself with parachute use and have an exhibition in Warsaw. In the photograph, one can see the tower from which the young Polish man was dropped. (Item 1)
    - Parachutes (Russia). (Envelope 7)
      - Photograph of parachute landing near Russian mansion; parachute with full opening. (Item 1)
      - Photograph at same Russian mansion, cloth fullness slowly depleting. (Item 2)
      - Two photographs of parachutists mid flight. (Item 3)
    - Parachutes. (Envelope 8)
  - Propellers. (Box 64)
    - Propellers (England). (Envelope 1)
    - Propellers (Germany). (Envelope 2)
    - Propellers (Italy). (Envelope 3)
    - Propeller (Russia) “Lebedeff.” (Envelope 4)
    - Propellers (USA). (Envelope 5)
    - Conducting Gear for Propellers. (Envelope 6)
    - Propellers (all countries). (Envelope 7)
    - Un-adjustable Propellers. (Envelope 8)
    - Propeller Vibrations (in flight). (Envelope 9)
  - Photos of Raids. (Box 65)
    - Raids (England). (Envelope 1)
      - Photograph of the “Pride of Detroit,” flown by William S. Brock and William F. Schlee in a round-the-world flight in 1927. Together, the aviators completed the eight non-stop flight across the Atlantic. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of the “Horsa” arriving in Khartoum, Sudan. The passengers include Sir Hubert and Lady Young, Dame Ethel Locke King and Lady Diana Gibbs. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of H.L Brook after setting a new speed record for travel between England and Australia with a time of 7 days 19 hours and 50 minutes, 1935. (Item 3)
      - Photograph taken shortly before the disappearance of famous aviator, Charles Ulm, 1934. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of “hydravions” of the Royal Air Force (R.A.F.) departing from Mount Batten, England, 1933. (Item 5)
      - Photograph of Scottish aviator, J.A. Mollison, leaving Ireland for a round-trip transatlantic flight (Item 6)
      - Two photographs of Gayford and Nicholetts surrounding their record-breaking flight from London to South Africa, 1933. (Item 7)
    - Balbo Raid. (Envelope 2)
      - Photograph taken in Rome after General Italo Balbo’s return flight from the World’s Fair in Chicago, 1933. (Item 1)
      - Photograph taken after General Balbo’s return flight. The picture shows soldiers marching through the Triumphal Arch of Constantine in Rome, 1933. (Item 2)
      - Three photographs of the twenty-four hydroplanes employed in Balbo’s transatlantic flight. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of a priest giving a blessing before the transatlantic flight. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of General Balbo’s arrival in Amsterdam on his way to the World’s Fair in Chicago. (Item 5)
      - Photograph of General Balbo addressing his pilots in Londonderry (Derry), England on his way to the World’s Fair in Chicago. (Item 6)
      - Three unidentified photographs of General Balbo’s flight. (Item 7)
    - “Juvisy Bagatelle” Raid, 1910. (Envelope 3)
      - Twenty-five photographs of Emile Dubonnet’s 1910 flight from Juvisy to Bagatelle with views over Paris (Eiffel Tower, Champs-Élysée, Place de la Concorde). (Item 1)
    - Saharan Raid (Before WWI). (Envelope 4)
      - Six photographs from a 1914 flight between Tunis, Tunisia and Oujda, Morocco with aerial views. (Item 1)
    - Records of Raids in Italy. (Envelope 5)
      - Photograph of Italian aviator Dr. L. Robiano after his record breaking flight from England to Australia. (Item 1)
    - Records of Raids Japan. (Envelope 6)
      - Photograph of an unidentified Japanese airplane. (Item 1)
    - Records of Raids Russia. (Envelope 7)
      - Three photographs of the Soviet transpolar flight, 1937 including pictures of pilot Gromoff, copilot Yumoshev and navigator Lanlin. (Item 1)
    - Records of Raids Sweden. (Envelope 8)
      - Two photographs of Kurt Bjöerkvall after the emergency landing off the Irish coast on his way to Stockholm, 1936. (Item 1)
    - Returning from Raids. (Envelope 9)
      - Photograph of Maryse Bastié sipping champagne with M. Caudron after her flight from France to South America, 1937. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of Maurice Noguès landing in Argenteuil, France, 1927. (Item 2)
      - Three photographs of Maryse Hilsz upon her return from Japan. (Item 3)
      - Three photographs of Maryse Bastié after her South American flight, 1937. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of Bailly, Resinensi and Marsot having returned from their flight from Paris to Indochina. (Item 5)
      - Three photographs of aviators Bernard and Bougault returning from their flight from France to Madagascar, 1927. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of Dieudonne Costes and Paul Codos after breaking the world record for distance in a closed circuit, 1929. (Item 7)
      - Three photographs of Dieudonne Costes and Joseph Le Brix after returning from their round-the-world flight, 1928. (Item 8)
      - Three photographs of Paul Codos after a return flight. (Item 9)
      - Three photographs of the aviators “Francais, Genin, Laurent and Robert after their record-breaking flight from France to Madagascar, 1935. (Item 10)
      - Photograph after a return flight from Tunis, 1933. (Item 11)
      - Six unidentified photographs taken after return flights. (Item 12)
    - Records of Raids USA. (Envelope 10)
      - Letter and twenty-three enclosed photographs of the 1938 National Air Races from Robert C. Morrison to L’Aérophile. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of Kenneth Kress and Glenn Englert during refueling. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of the officers and crews of five American hydroplanes after breaking General Balbo’s record. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of the aviators Merrill and Richmann after traveling from New York to London, 1936. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of the airplane “Century of Progress” flown by Jimmie Mattern. Picture taken after his 1933 flight to Omsk, Siberia. (Item 5)
      - Photograph of Joseph and Benjamin Adamowicz after their 1934 transatlantic flight. (Item 6)
      - Photograph of Rear Admiral Richard Byrd’s airplane used in an Antarctic Expedition, 1934. (Item 7)
      - Photograph taken after a flight from California to Honolulu, 1934. (Item 8)
    - Records of Raids. (Envelope 11)
      - Three photographs of the airplane “Trait d’Union.” (Item 1)
      - Photograph depicting an early method of mid-air refueling. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of “grand raid autour de l'Allemagne,” 1933. The picture depicts Nazi planes preparing to depart. (Item 3)
      - Photograph of Dieudonnne Costes and Joseph Le Brix in Rio De Janeiro. (Item 4)
      - Two unidentified photographs of return flights. (Item 5)
      - Three photographs “Raid Amérique Sud Par Bossoutrot Rossé.” (Item 6)
      - Three photographs “Raid Europe Orientale Sur Bréguet.” (Item 7)
      - Photograph “Course Istres-Damas Paris Sur Bréguet”, 1938. (Item 8)
      - Six photographs “Voyage aux Etats-Unis Sur Bréguet” including a picture taken at Mitchell Field, New York. (Item 9)
      - Photograph “Raid Paris Le Cap Sur Caudron.” (Item 10)
      - Two photographs “Raid Paris Omsk Sur Bréguet” 1926. (Item 11)
      - Twelve photographs “Raid Paris-Saigon Sur Bréguet Sur S.P.C.A. & Maillet.” (Item 12)
      - Two photographs “Raid Paris-Tokyo et Paris-Hanoi-Tokyo Sur Bréguet.” (Item 13)
      - Eleven photographs “Raids Cadosa Rossé.” (Item 14)
  - Research/Testing. (Box 66)
    - Research, Tests and Inventions before WWI. (Envelope 1)
    - Astronautics Tests (France). (Envelope 2)
    - Research Test Photographs. (Envelope 3)
    - Astronautics Tests (Germany). (Envelope 4)
    - Astronautics Tests (USA). (Envelope 5)
  - New Technology. (Box 67)
    - Aerodynamic Techniques. (Envelope 1)
    - Applied Techniques (England). (Envelope 2)
    - Applied Techniques (France). (Envelope 3)
    - Applied Techniques (Germany). (Envelope 4)
    - Applied Techniques (USA). (Envelope 5)
    - Experimental Techniques (England). (Envelope 6)
    - Experimental Techniques (France). (Envelope 7)
    - Experimental Techniques (Italy). (Envelope 8)
    - Experimental Techniques (USA). (Envelope 9)
    - Timing and Registration Applied Techniques. (Envelope 10)
  - Commercial, medical and military-medical aviation. (Box 68)
    - Colonial Aviation (France). (Envelope 1)
    - Commercial Aviation (France). (Envelope 2)
    - Military Aviation (England) “Concours Militaire Anglais.” (Envelope 3)
    - Medical Aviation (Italy). (Envelope 4)
    - Medical Aviation (France). (Envelope 5)
    - Military Aviation #2. (Envelope 6)
  - Alaska Flight 1934 (U.S.); Army-Air generals (U.S.). (Box 69)
    - U.S Alaskan Flight, July/August 1934 #1. (Envelope 1)
      - Three photographs of group gathering in woods with women. Pictured include Majs. Ralph Royce (left of woman in printed dress), Maj. Hugh J. Kerr (left of woman in white-buttoned dress) and Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold (right of woman in white-buttoned dress). (Item 1)
      - Photograph of Majs. Ralph Royce Hugh J. Knerr examining an Alaskan map. (Item 2)
      - Two photographs of Maj. Hugh J. Knerr with other crew members in front of B-10 plane. (Item 3)
      - One photograph of Maj. Hugh J. Knerr by himself in front of B-10 plane. (Item 4)
      - Two photographs of Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold pushing dolly of three crates marked, “Associated Oil Co.” Maj. Hugh J. Knerr is directing the delivery in Fairbanks. (Item 5)
      - Two photographs of crew members in front of grounded plane. Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold is center holding heart-shaped sign which says, “Fairbanks Alaska Golden Heart.” Maj. Hugh J. Knerr is pictured fifth from left. (Item 6)
      - Maj. Hugh J. Knerr lounging at desk holding a copy of “Sunday Mirror.” Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold is peering over Knerr’s shoulder. (Item 7)
      - Four photographs of crew members examining fish on a Fairbanks sidewalk outside the Barber shop. Maj. Hugh J. Knerr is shown in one. (Item 8)
      - Two photographs of unidentified crew member (donning glasses) interacting with chained young black bears (feeding and washing). One photograph of shows a young black bear. (Item 9)
      - Two photographs of a young ram. (Item 10)
      - Six photographs of Martin B-10s. (Item 11)
      - Two photographs of campsite. (Item 12)
      - One photograph of chained off steam engine car marked, “A.R.R. 1.” (Item 13)
      - One photograph of garden outside living quarters. (Item 14)
      - Three photographs of living quarters. (Item 15)
      - Photograph of two unidentified crew members next to totem pole. (Item 16)
      - Same crew members from ITEM 16 after hunting, holding animal hides (Item 17)
      - Five crew members in the field. Maj. Hugh J. Knerr is first from the right. (Item 18)
      - Three photographs of local town and shipyard. (Item 19)
      - One photograph of deer standing alone on an unpaved road. (Item 20)
      - Eight aerial photographs of unidentified glaciers and mountains. (Item 21)
      - Five aerial photographs of flat land, lakes and trees. (Item 22)
      - Three aerial photographs of Alaskan towns. (Item 23)
      - One aerial photograph of Alaskan farm. (Item 24)
      - One aerial photograph of Gold Dudge near Fairbanks, Alaska, 1934. (Item 25)
      - Six aerial photographs of Alaskan lakes and flatlands. (Item 26)
      - Two aerial photographs of a Fairbanks bridge. (Item 27)
      - Aerial photograph of Alaskan. (Item 28)
      - Two large aerial photographs of Anchorage airport. (Item 29)
      - Three large aerial photographs of Alaskan glaciers. (Item 30)
      - Aerial photograph of glacier near Circle, Alaska. (Item 31)
      - Two large photographs of Martin B-10 crash. (Item 32)
      - Large photograph of Capt. Bobzien who was forced to landed at Cook’s Inlet on August 3, 1934. (Item 33)
      - Aerial photograph of farm on the edge of town. (Item 34)
    - U.S Alaskan Flight July/August 1934 #2. (Envelope 2)
      - Photograph of Asst. Sec. of War Harry Hines Woodring, Gen. Benjamin Foulois and Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of Asst. Sec. of Defense Harry Hines Woodring shaking hands with Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold. (Item 2)
      - Five photographs of Asst. Sec. of War Harry Hines Woodring with crew members. (Item 3)
      - Two photographs of crew members next to B-10 Martin. (Item 4)
      - Photograph of Gen. Hugh J. Knerr crouched holding a small husky dog with two unidentified crew members. (Item 5)
      - Individual photograph of Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold. (Item 6)
      - Two photographs of crew members examining fish on the boardwalk. (Item 7)
      - Two photographs of crew members in the woods. (Item 8)
      - Photograph of crew member seated in the cockpit. (Item 9)
      - Photograph of three unidentified crew members in front of Martin B-10. (Item 10)
      - Four photographs of a skull and tusks of a prehistoric animal dug up near Fairbanks. Estimated at six million years. (Item 11)
      - Eleven photographs of Martin B-10s. (Item 12)
      - Photograph of two crew members in front of “Twelve Mile Roadhouse.” (Item 13)
      - Photograph of Alaska Oil pipeline. (Item 14)
      - Photograph of Lt. Col. Henry H. “Hap” Arnold pushing dolly of three crates marked, “Associated Oil Co.” Maj. Hugh J. Knerr is directing the delivery in Fairbanks. (Item 15)
      - Two photographs of Fairbanks airport. (Item 16)
      - Four large photographs of Martin B-10 in flight. (Item 17)
      - Photograph of midnight sun on the Yukon. (Item 18)
      - Two aerial views of Gold Dudge. (Item 19)
      - Two photographs forest and lakes. (Item 20)
      - Nine aerial photographs of glaciers and lakes. (Item 21)
      - Three aerial photographs of Fairbanks. (Item 22)
      - Aerial photograph of farm. (Item 23)
      - Aerial photograph of bridge. (Item 24)
      - Photograph of airborne Martin B-10. (Item 25)
      - Photograph of local main street. (Item 26)
      - Three unidentified photographs. (Item 27)
    - U.S Army Generals. (Envelope 3)
      - Portrait photograph of Brigadier General William “Billy” Mitchell. (Item 1)
      - Portrait photograph of Gen. Carl Spaatz. (Item 2)
  - Bombs and missiles: Atomic Bomb, V1, Civil Air Defense, guided missiles, Pearl Harbor, war photos (WWII). (Box 70)
    - Pearl Harbor. (Envelope 1)
      - Photograph of the U.S.S. West Virginia, U.S.S. Tennessee and the U.S.S. Arizona. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of the U.S.S. Helena damaged by Japanese torpedoes. (Item 2)
      - Photograph of a small boat rescuing sailors from the U.S.S. West Virginia. (Item 3)
    - The Atomic Bomb. (Envelope 2)
      - Twenty photographs of atomic bomb testing including pictures of Bikini Atoll tests, underwater detonations, TNT tests in the San Diego Bay and “Operation Crossroads.” (Item 1)
    - V1 Bomb (Germany). (Envelope 3)
      - Photograph of the V1 bomb. (Item 1)
    - Cannons. (Envelope 4)
      - Two clippings and one photograph of cannons or early anti-aircraft guns. (Item 1)
    - Catapults. (Envelope 5)
      - Photograph of an amphibious aircraft launched from a catapult in Farnborough, England. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of the Minister of Air catapulted at the “manoeuvres aeriennes” held in Toulon. (Item 2)
      - Two attached photographs of W.B Wheatley’s plane before and after it was catapulted. (Item 3)
    - Civil Air Defense (France) Photographs and Diagram. (Envelope 6)
      - Eight photographs of exercises, posters and equipment used by the Civil Air Defense, 1936-1939. (Item 1)
      - Three diagrams depicting the intensity of underground and above-ground explosives on buildings. (Item 2)
    - NATIV Guided Missile. (Envelope 7)
      - Press release and five photographs of “the North American Aviation guided missile NATIV,”, 1949. (Item 1)
    - Photos from WWII (England). (Envelope 8)
      - Photograph of two members of the Royal Army Service Corps. (Item 1)
      - Photograph of a woman wearing a parachute. (Item 2)